Guide to the Spectrum records, 1993-2004.
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Spectrum records 1993-2004
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Spectrum.
0.7 Linear Feet 750 Items
Spectrum is an organization at Duke University that serves as a vehicle for inter-community dialogue and collaboration among the various cultural groups including: The Asian Student Association, Black Student Alliance, Duke India Association, Hillel, Mi Gente, Diya, Native American Studies Coalition, Spectrum Dormitory, and the Students of the Caribbean Association.
The collection includes reports, proposals, articles, agendas, brochures, notes, and various materials on the construction and expansion of a multicultural center as well as other social and cultural spaces on campus.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Spectrum records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in April 22, 2005.
Historical Note
Spectrum is an organization at Duke University that serves as a vehicle for inter-community dialogue and collaboration among the various cultural groups including: The Asian Student Association, Black Student Alliance, Duke India Association, Hillel, Mi Gente, Diya, Native American Studies Coalition, Spectrum Dormitory, and the Students of the Caribbean Association. Spectrum was founded in 1988 by students of color under the guidance of Dr. Edward Hill, director of the Mary Lou Williams Center, as a support network for minority cultural groups on campus. Over the past years Spectrum has submitted numerous proposals to improve social and cultural spaces on campus for the benefit of all students, has spearheaded leadership events, and has supported the notion of 'unity through diversity.'
Collection Overview
The collection includes reports, proposals, articles, agendas, brochures, notes, and various materials on the construction and expansion of a multicultural center as well as other social and cultural spaces on campus. Items in the collection range in date from 1993-2004.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Spectrum
Duke University. Asian Students Association
Duke University. Black Student Alliance
Duke University. Diya
Duke University. Hillel
Duke University. Mi Gente
Duke University. Native American Student Alliance
Duke University. Students of the Caribbean
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Related Material
Inventory of the Asian Students Association records, 1995-2005.
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the Black Student Alliance records, 1969-2006.
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the Diya Records, 1992-2006.
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the Living Groups Reference Collection, 1964-ongoing.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Spectrum Records, 1993-2004, 1 Box
  - About the organization (mission statement, constitution, etc…), 1993-2002 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1993, 2001, undated
  - Correspondence, 1994-2002
  - Event Information, 1994-2001
  - Meeting binder, 2000-2001
  - Minutes, agendas, memoranda, 1994, 2000-2001
  - Miscellaneous documents, 2001-2002, undated
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated
  - Proposals and Recommendations (various), 2001-2004, undated
  - Recommendations and Information concerning Cultural Space, 2000-2001
  - Recommendations and Information concerning Social Space, 1996-2001
  - Residence life at Duke, 1994-2001